<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>abiramen's site</title><link>https://abiram.me/</link><description>Recent content on abiramen's site</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://abiram.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>CompClub CTF 2022</title><link>https://abiram.me/compclub-2022/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://abiram.me/compclub-2022/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="behind-the-scenes"&gt;Behind the scenes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Setting up infrastructure was much easier this year - being CSESoc&amp;rsquo;s Technical Director meant I had access to a server to host a CTF. The only other challenge that required hosting was lightweight enough for me to run on my spare VPS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Huge shoutout to Felix and Paula again for their help with writing up challenges this year!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="challenges-and-solutions"&gt;Challenges and solutions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are all the challenges! The solutions are hidden until you click on them, so that you can try challenges without spoilers.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>CSE and VS Code</title><link>https://abiram.me/cse-setup/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://abiram.me/cse-setup/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re going to be setting up a text editor called Visual Studio Code, or VS Code, to remotely work on the CSE computers without needing a VNC client!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="why-are-we-doing-this"&gt;Why are we doing this?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ve likely used a program called TigerVNC to connect to the School of CSE&amp;rsquo;s computers before, which provides you a visual interface with a full desktop environment. f you&amp;rsquo;re currently doing COMP1511, I would strongly advise you to use the provided desktop environment and gedit over TigerVNC for the first week, just to familiarise yourself with it.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>CSE and SSHFS</title><link>https://abiram.me/cse-sshfs/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://abiram.me/cse-sshfs/</guid><description>&lt;div class="alert "&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re a VS Code user who is in first year, or isn&amp;rsquo;t too used to coding locally, you might be better off checking the easier method of using SSHFS with VS Code &lt;a href="https://abiram.me/cse-setup"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;
.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello! About a year and a half ago, I wrote a blogpost about setting up Visual Studio Code to connect to CSE machines using the &amp;lsquo;Remote - SSH&amp;rsquo; extension.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In hindsight, this was a &lt;strong&gt;terrible mistake&lt;/strong&gt; with consequences I could not have foreseen. It turns out that the extension spawns a nodejs server on the remote machine for each connection, which requires an &lt;em&gt;intense&lt;/em&gt; amount of resources &lt;sup id="fnref:1"&gt;&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>CompClub CTF 2021</title><link>https://abiram.me/compclub-2021/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://abiram.me/compclub-2021/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking for the opportunity to do some form of high school outreach program for a while, so when CSESoc&amp;rsquo;s (my uni&amp;rsquo;s constituent society for computer science related degrees) CompClub decided to take applications for workshop developers, and saw the option for a security workshop, I knew I had to sign up. The following CTF was the result of my work with the help of a few fellow fantastic volunteers.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>CSE and VS Code (archive)</title><link>https://abiram.me/cse-setup-legacy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://abiram.me/cse-setup-legacy/</guid><description>&lt;div class="alert alert-red"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WARNING&lt;/strong&gt; This method is now considered unreliable due to the load it places on CSE servers, and may be blocked by CSE&amp;rsquo;s System Support at any time. Check out &lt;a href="https://abiram.me/cse-setup"&gt;this newer post&lt;/a&gt;
 instead. Do not use this on CSE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi there! If you&amp;rsquo;re new here, welcome to CSE! We&amp;rsquo;re going to be setting up a text editor called Visual Studio Code, or VS Code, to remotely work on the CSE computers without needing a VNC client!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Setting up WSL and GitHub (archive)</title><link>https://abiram.me/wsl-github/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://abiram.me/wsl-github/</guid><description>&lt;div class="alert alert-red"&gt;
 This post is no longer up to date. I generally now advise most people use WSL 2. I may or may not write an updated version of this post in the future.
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
 If you're a UNSW student, there's a good chance that you're here from my CSE setup guide for vscode.
 This is
 going to be a short guide to setting up WSL, which provides you with a Linux environment within Windows. To go
 through
 the WSL section, you'll need to be on Windows 10. If you're here just to learn some basic Git, you can
 &lt;a href="#git"&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt; to skip all the Windows stuff, free of charge!
&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>about</title><link>https://abiram.me/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://abiram.me/about/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="im-abiram"&gt;i&amp;rsquo;m abiram&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and i haven&amp;rsquo;t completed this page&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>